Let's be real, most traders understand
smart money concept, but they are still
struggling with entries. It's either
they take their entries too early, too
late, or at the wrong place entirely.
So, make sure you watch this video to
the very end because at the end of this
video, I'll be able to open your eyes on
how to take entries from the safest spot
on the chart, how to take that refined
entry and get beautiful point of
interest that would dish out the move
for you. So, watch to the very end and
don't forget to like, subscribe, and
turn on the notification bell. Let's go
to the charts, guys.
So, traders, when it comes to entry, I
have two entry models that I work with
and they are the aggressive entry and
the confirmation entry. So, make sure
you watch this video to the very end
because I'm going to pick them one after
the other and explain how and when you
need to take these entries, when to take
the aggressive entry and when to take
confirmation entry. So, we're going to
pick them one after the other. Let's
start with aggressive entry. So, for
aggressive entry, I've been able to, you
know, write out few stuff here. So from
the screen you can see that this is best
used when the trend is strong for a
trend continuation entry and then when
we are looking at the time frame it's
best used in 15 minutes time frame and
note all conflences must be intact that
simply means the recent break of
structure must be there you map out the
other block liquidity and inbalance then
execution how to set this type of entry
is by just putting your pending order,
applying proper risk management. I'll
also show you guys this on the chart.
I've also been able to map out when to
avoid aggressive entry. So, when it
comes to aggressive entry, avoid
aggressive entry when the zone has been
tapped before. If the other block you're
trying to take this entry from has been
mitigated before, avoid taking
aggressive entry from that particular
order block. And then avoid taking
aggressive entry when market is
consolidating when there is no clear
liquidity sweep and when you are not
mentally calm or focused. So please take
note of this. We'll still go to the
chart and you will see reasons with me
why you need to avoid aggressive entry
when zone has been tapped into market is
consolidating no clear liquidity sweep
and when you are not mentally calm and
focused. So that is it for aggressive
entry. Let's quickly run through
confirmation entry. So for confirmation
entry, confirmation entry means you
don't take trade just because price
reaches a zone. So the zone can be order
block, FVG and other zones. You wait for
price to show intent, emphasis on
intent. You wait for price to show
intent
through structure shift or reaction
before entering. So that is it for
confirmation entry. So let me also show
you guys when to use confirmation entry.
So for confirmation entry you use
confirmation entry when zone has been
mitigated before. If that particular
order block has been tapped into you
know that is when you need to work with
confirmation. If price is trying to come
back there again then when the market is
consolidating and you've seen a certain
structure you also need to wait for
confirmation to know whether price is
indeed trying to move to the you know
direction you want it to go to or if
it's trying to go south and then when
the trend is uncertain that is you are
certain about the trend or bias you work
with confirmation and when price is
reacting to a support or resistance
level. That is when to use confirmation.
I've also been able to map out um what
to wait for if you want to work with
confirmation entry. So pay close
attention. So if you want to work with
confirmation entry, these are different
steps you need to work with. You need to
wait for this. Now you need to wait for
price to tap into that POI. So remember
from the last slide I just showed you
when to use confirmation entry. So I
said when um the zone has been mitigated
or support and resistant level at the
rest. So when price taps into that zone
you need to wait for what the second one
that is internal break of structure or
change of character. So have it in mind
that the zone price is tapping into must
be a clean high probability zone. The
zone must have created you know breakup
structure pointing to the trend that is
visible on the chart. Then once price
stops into that your POI you start
looking for internal break of structures
or change of character. So the time
frame you need to start looking for this
will be the 3 minute time frame and 1
minute time frame. So between these two
some can touch that of five minutes and
the rest but three minute and um 1
minute is okay. So once you get the
internal break structure or change of
character it shows price is rejecting
from the zone and shifting direction
then this is the next thing you will do.
Your entry will be on the pullback of
the lower time frame order block or FVG
depending on the one you use to take
your entry. So once you get that
internal breakoff structure from the
lower time frame, your entry will be on
the other block that caused that
internal break of structure. Once you
get um a change of character, your entry
will be on the other block that caused
the change of character in the lower
time frame. So just check it here. After
change of character, wait for price to
return to the refined zone.
That will be your entry point and your
stop loss will be below the recent high
or low depending on what you are looking
out for. So the next thing on the list
is when to avoid confirmation entry. You
avoid confirmation entry when the market
momentum is very high. when there is
high volatility because when you are
trying to take confirmation entry when
there is high volatility you may miss
your entry because price may not have
time to come and start giving you all
those internal structures and the rest
so I believe that is it we going to go
to the chart now and I'll show you guys
examples of aggressive entry you know
how to actually take it just like I've
been able to you know show you guys here
theoretically and also that of
confirmation entry. So, let's go to the
chart. Okay, traders, from this chart,
you can obviously see that the market is
pointing to the downside because we got
this clean break of structure at this
point. So, you can see that we have a
very clean break of structure at this
point. Once you get your break of
structure, you start looking for the
origin that caused that break of
structure. That is the other block. So,
you can see where the other block is at.
The other block is here. So, now this is
15 minutes. So this is also a clean
trade I was able to catch from 15
minutes. I had to put my pending order
here because all the confluences I
needed on the ch on this chart they are
intact. We've gotten the trend now a
clean break of structure to the
downside. My other block and then FVG
intact here and then liquidity price
will clear is here. So in this type of
situation I will take my aggressive
entry here. Then my stop loss will now
be a little bit above the last week
rejection. That will be where my stop
loss would be. And then I will target
the point of retracement. So it was a
trade of one is to two risk-to-reward
ratio. So here my pending order will be
set here. So all I just want the market
to do will be for it to come mitigate
this point and then move to the
direction. So the chart is on replay
mode. Let's play so that you'll see how
price reacted off the zone. Let's go
ahead and play the chart
so that you'll see how price reacted.
Now you can see price has mitigated the
zone. So as price has tapped into this
point, it has triggered my entry and my
entry is running. If it's a good tread,
it's going to go straight to my TP, give
me money, and that will be all. And then
if it's a bad trade, it's going straight
to my SL, you know, give me losses and
that will be all. So this was indeed a
successful one. So price tapped in and
you can see how it moved straight to TP.
So I worked with aggressive entry on
this particular trade. But now like I
said, I used aggressive entry. We are
still going to check. Let's assume I
wanted to use confirmation entry on this
particular setup. Let's see whether I
would have also you know gotten an
entry. So let's start from the 1 minute
time frame. Let's view from 1 minute
time frame.
Let's see if I'll be able to get
an entry opportunity if I used
um
confirmation entry.
So let's see. Okay. So from 1 minute
time frame I'm already seeing something.
Let me just refresh the charts so that
it should be bold.
Okay. So let me take away this two. So
from 1 minute time frame you can see
after price cleared the liquidity.
I think there is also confirmation entry
here. So after price cleared the
liquidity you can see when price tapped
into
the other block.
So from 1 minute time frame that created
what a break of structure to the upside
which was the last break of structure to
the upside.
Now after that
price started retracing
to the downside. So now this was where
the change of character occurred
generally.
Change of character occurred here
generally. So if I'm looking to take
entries, I'll have to look for the other
block that caused this particular change
of character. So for the other block
that cost this particular change of
character, if I'm to map it out, it will
be here.
It will be here. So that simply means
from 1 minute I will miss this entry.
I'll miss this entry from 1 minute time
frame. Let's check 3 minutes if we'll be
able to catch the entry. If we wanted to
work with confirmation.
Okay, from 3 minutes time frame. So 3
minute time frame, this will now be the
other block because 1 minute was kind of
refined. So we are still working with
the last break of structure to the
upside. And now change of character the
origin that caused the change of
character. This will be the other block.
So I'll map it out. So let's check
whether price. Let's highlight it. Well,
okay. You can see from 3 minutes if I
wanted to work with confirmation entry 3
minutes gave me the confirmation I
needed. So the confirmation here
remember the explanation allow price to
show you intent that it is ready to move
before you enter. So you can see price
rejecting from here giving me a change
of character. Now coming back into the
origin once I get this change of
character that is now when
I will be looking to take my entries.
Now stop loss will now be above
the order block that is the new order
block from the lower time frame that I'm
trying to work with which is this one.
That is where my stop loss will be just
above here. So here stop loss will be
around 25 pips. So one thing with
confirmation entry is that you will get
a well refined stop loss. So
let's check the risk-to-reward ratio the
trade will give to us because we'll
still be targeting this point as our
take profit. So here the riskto-reward
ratio will now be 1 is to six compared
to let's let me check my aggressive
entry. So my aggressive entry I took
entry from here stop loss a little bit
above this point. So aggressive entry
gave me risk-to-reward ratio of 1 is to
two because obviously my stop loss was
you know way bigger than this but then
confirmation dished out you know a well
refined risk-to-reward ratio that is 1
is to six so it all depends on the one
you want to work with for me sometimes I
work with confirmation sometimes just
depending on the momentum from what I've
explained sometimes I work with
aggressive but then looking at this
trade now confirm Confirmation gave a
better risk-to-reward ratio. Although
aggressive entry gave us early entry
into the trade but confirmation gave
sweet risk-to-reward ratio. So that is
it. Let's also look at another example.
So trader still on gold. Remember we
were able to catch this particular cell.
Now we have a new break of structure.
Now from this breakup structure we need
to look for the other block that caused
this particular break of structure. So
from this particular order block looking
at the origin.
So you can see the origin started from
here to this point. So inside this
origin you have to look for the other
block that caused this particular break
structure. So now from this particular
origin, if I'm to map out the other
block, this will be the other block.
This right here will be the other block.
But then if I'm trying to take this type
of trade as an aggressive entry, where
to place my SL will be an issue for me
considering how the origin is looking.
So when I am faced with this challenge,
that is now when um
um confirmation entry will come in. So
for this one, we're going to work with
confirmation entry. So let's play the
chart to see if we will catch this
particular setup or not. So let's see
what price did when it tapped into the
other block. So you can see price has
mitigated the other block. So what we're
going to do now, we're going to go down
to 1 minute first.
Let's go to 1 minute time frame and
start looking for confirmation as price
has mitigated the other block. So you
can see from here price
tapped into the other block
giving us what
we have this break of structure here
which was the last break of structure to
the upside. Now from here
price dished out a change of character.
Now for the origin that caused this
change of character it will be here.
The origin that caused this change of
character
it will be somewhere here.
So let's see whether price
will push down. Now, if we are trying to
catch this,
if we're trying to catch this, our
takerit
will be at this point. Now, if we're
trying to catch this, it will just be
the entry will be like this. And now,
take profit will be here because this is
the point of retracement. Just something
like this. That's where our take profit
will be. So it would just be an entry of
you know you're risking 13 pips to catch
48 pips on XAUSD. But then if it was
from 15 minutes our take profit
we would have been considering this
level. So let's see. But from 1 minute
this is the confirmation entry that is
present. Let's see if this one was able
to hit. Okay. Now you can see from this
particular confirmation entry, this one
was a bad one. So although price is
still reacting to this particular order
block, we need to observe. So price
wasn't ready to move here. Price is
still reacting to the order block. So
this was a bad one. Let's look for
another point of interest or another
reason to enter another confirmation. So
price is back to the order block. Let's
play the chart.
on the next line of action.
Now you can see what the market did
here. This will no longer be a change of
character because price came back here
to mitigate
just this origin at this point. So we'll
have this break of structure here
and then price created this particular
break of structure here. So aggressive
entry will no longer be in the picture
because price has mitigated the origin
you know countless times. So we we just
need to work with confirmation. So let's
take this away. This one was a bad
entry.
So now we have this record of structure
from here. We also have this particular
order block which may be sending the
price up. So this is also another way to
you know take an entry. But now price is
reacting to a supply zone. Will you be
confident enough to take this particular
buy to the upside since that is you know
the confirmation price is given here
following that the change of character
that occurred here you know changed back
to a bullish trend. So let's see
let's see trying to catch this buy
continuation here
your stop loss will be a little bit
below the last week rejection
and then take profit will be here. So
let's see if it's a trade of you know a
good risk-to-reward ratio. So leaving
the take profit here it will just be a
trade of approximately 1 is to2 but it's
not one is to two in full. So that's not
a good trade of you know a good thread
to risk unless you want to target this
resistance level. So let's see if that
will happen. So targeting this
resistance level it's now a good risk to
what ratio. So
let's shift this. Let's see if price
will respect it. So, let's play the
chart. So, we'll take away the the buy
and just focus more on the um sell
confirmation we're waiting for. Let's
see what price would do.
So, let's see. Let's play the chart. So,
price is literally ranging around this
order block,
but there is no clean confirmation yet.
Now we still rallying to the upside.
So that simply means this order block is
no longer in the picture. We are no
longer looking for confirmation from
this order block. So going back to 15
minutes, let's see where price is headed
and if we should keep looking for a sell
or a buy. Now from here price is no
longer respecting the order block.
Instead it's trying to react to this
particular resistance level here.
So let's just map out the resistance
level.
Let's see what price will do now. Price
has stopped into the resistance level.
We'll still go back to 1 minute time
frame.
Let's see.
So, one thing about confirmation entry
is that you need to follow the market
back to back and open your eyes when
you're trying to catch it or you will
still miss the entry.
Okay.
So, price has reacted to the resistance
level again rejected. Now what I can see
here is
um although this is a weak rejection
break but generally this will be where
the break of structure. If we are
looking for the last break of structure
it would be at this point. The last
break of structure
is here. So if we are looking for change
of character it will be here. But then
let's see what the market will do
whether we'll get a change of character
or an internal break structure.
So let's see.
Okay. Now
because this is a weak rejection break
structure so I will not call this a
change of character. I can call it
internal breakoff structure.
Now from this internal break of
structure
where is the origin that caused this
internal break of structure? So
generally all this consolidation here
that's the origin. But now if we're
trying to map out the other block it
will be this blue candlestick. So it's
looking as if the market is ready. So
let's see to be this blue candlestick
and then entry will now be here.
Then for stop loss a little bit above
the last week rejection
for the other block. Then
take profit will obviously be here. This
is the point of um reversal as far as
was pushing up. So take profit will
obviously be here. But if it's um 15
minutes we'll be targeting this point.
But since we did not take entries from
15 minutes. So we just have two points
we are waiting for here that is the 1
minute we can call this one TP1 and TP2
if we want to scale it. So the line will
be there. This will be for TP1. So let's
see if we'll be able to achieve
everything here. So looking at this
confirmation entry now it's giving us
risk-to-reward ratio of 1 is to 9. So
let's see because here stop loss is just
12 pips or let's make it
13 because I want to consider the FVG
here.
So let's just move our stop loss. So
let's see if price would dish out the
move. If this does not give us the
movement then we know that there is no
entry for us. will start looking for
another,
you know, reason to
buy gold because the sellers cuz if you
break everything and keep pushing up,
that simply means the buyers are still
in and gold is not ready for a sell.
Okay, so entry triggered here. Entry
triggered here and it's looking nice
nice
for the confirmation entry. So at the
end of the day, we're able to catch the
cell on gold, you know, following it
back to back. So like I said, you need
to open your eyes when you're trying to
catch the confirmation entry. So from
what I've noticed from back testing and
you know, most of the times when I use
confirmation entry, it gives better
risk-to-reward ratio. So this one now is
1 is to 9. Let's see if we'll be able to
catch that in full. Remember first TP
here. So if price should come here, you
should be looking to book partials. So
let's see.
Let's see.
Okay.
Too much range at the moment, but we are
still in profit.
Okay.
Price almost at TP1.
Okay, TP1 smashed here and it is still
dipping.
It is still dipping.
So, TP1 was able to give us how many
risk to reward ratio?
So, TP1
was 1 is to 4 risk-to-reward ratio,
which you know, it's also a decent
trade. But now let's see if we'll get it
in full. We're almost there. We're
almost there at 1 is to 9 risk-to-reward
ratio working with confirmation. So
let's finish that up and see whether
price
indeed mitigated
the zone.
Okay.
So this was a decent trade full CP. Now
pay attention on the entry.
Pay attention on the entry. So guys, you
can see how this particular trade was
able to give us a decent you know one is
to 9 risk-to-reward ratio. So if you
check
how we got the entry a clean
confirmation entry that is what you need
to open your eyes to observe whenever
you are trying to catch this type of
setup especially that of confirmation
entry. Now you can see from the
different examples you will notice that
confirmation entry gives us a well
refined entry and also a well refined
stop- loss more like very tight
stop-loss which will help increase the
risk-to-reward ratio. So this was also a
decent trade on XAUSD. Let's get some
examples from GBP JPY. Okay traders from
this clip movement here on GBP JPY
um you can see that we have a break of
structure at this point and also another
break of structure at this point
but now from 15 minutes I'll be
considering this particular level
which is this point here that is where
I'll be looking to catch this particular
trade aggressively
while this would be my liquidity zone
more like an inducement level.
So
it was also a very clean setup. I was
also able to catch but I'm just walking
you guys through the processes.
So now you can also see my FVG intact.
So remember the criteria on the
conditions you need to meet before you
work with aggressive entry. Make sure
you're aligning with the trend and make
sure all the complences are intact. So
now
having all these things in place, I will
just put my pending order stop loss a
little bit, you know, below the last
week rejection just somewhere here
or let's just keep it here. Then um TP
will be at the point of reversal which
is somewhere here. So this is a trade of
one is to two reward ratio. So once I
see it like this I will put my you know
pending order waiting for price to come
and mitigate. So I can see let's see how
price reacted.
Okay immediately we got this sharp
movement. Now this is also this
particular movement. Now you cannot
catch it you know with a confirmation
entry because you can see how price
tapped in aggressively to here it will
just mitigate the order or activate the
order here and then move straight to the
direction you can see almost at you know
TP or TP even smashed at this point.
So price just tapped in and boom to the
upside. Now this particular setup does
not need confirmation entry just because
of market momentum. Can see the push. So
here aggressive entry will be you know
what will be favorable because if we go
to let's check from 1 minute time frame
and see if we're working with
confirmation. You can see how fast that
happened. It will not show. You can see
there's no confirmation here. This you
know now where you know price showed a
little confirmation for you know a
continuation by let's also check from 3
minutes. So you can also see from 3
minutes no confirmation it was a sharp
movement to the upside. So this one is
more favorable to aggressive entry
traders. Let's also look at one more
example. This is another example on GBP
JJPY. So after that particular movement,
price dished out a decent break of
structure. But now looking at the
origin, it's more like um a support
level cuz the origin is not that
inviting. If we're looking for the other
block, generally this is where the order
block will be for this particular
origin. But price may want to
you know price may want to visit
everything here you know in it says you
know stopping us out and moving to
direction. So when the origin is like
this I always work with confirmation
entry because I'm expecting price to
like clear everything here you know try
to grab all the liquidity before it to
move. So I'll just map this out as
support level. Let's see if price will
come there.
So let me play the chart.
Now price is on the support and it's
reacting. Okay, I played the chart so
far. So you can obviously see that it
has rejected and it is dishing out a
clean buy. But let's quickly go down to
1 minute to see if that um this
particular buy the confirmation showed
up.
So let's check
now from 1 minute what do we have?
This was the last break of structure
before price tapped into
this particular support level
and then
um a change of character at this point.
So from this change of character this
let's move this a little. So this will
be the other block that caused this
particular change of character but price
didn't come there. It's looking as if it
reacted off the FVG.
So here now from 1 minute um the price
reacted from the FVG dishing out
confirmation. So if you take entries
from FVG this is where you'll be
catching it from stop loss a little bit
below the FVG and then you take it off.
So for 1 minute the confirmation tapped
into FVG but now let's check from 3
minutes whether okay 3 minutes it's
um favorable to other block traders
because from 3 minutes we are still
having the break of structure to the
downside when price tapped into the
support level change of character and
now you can see the other block here in
full
and price tapped in. So this
will be another confirmation price a
little bit below
and then we'll start targeting
the point of retracement which is this
point. So the confirmation was very
clean and it has refined it. So if we
target this point how many risk to
reward ratio. So this would be 1 is to 4
just 11 pips stop loss to catch 53 pips.
So, let's play the chart to see if this
was able to give us full TP.
Okay.
Okay. Price is indeed moving decently
to the upside.
Okay. Now I can also say something a
little retracement but inside that
retracement
look at this too
which would be an opportunity to add
positions if you're trying to scaling
stop loss a little bit below and then
you'll still be targeting same TP. So
inside one trade you've been able to you
know catch two trades and this one is
given 1 is to six risk-to-reward ratio.
So let's see
how much it will dish out in full
whether the two of them will go straight
to TP.
Okay,
chart is moving
clearly to the direction.
Interesting. A very decent buy indeed.
Foot tip is smashed and price is still
pushing up. Foot tip is smashed. Price
is still pushing up. So this is for you
to know that it works whether the
aggressive entry or confirmation entry.
But from this video I'm finding
confirmation entry more interesting. But
then you will be able to find this like
I said if you follow the market you know
back to back make sure you open your
eyes to see all these internal
structures because sometimes they will
not be too obvious
but then if you see all these internal
structures you'll be able to milk the
market. So these are ways to take your
entries aggressive entry or confirmation
entry. I use the two of them, but like I
stated with this video, confirmation
entry is more interesting. But there are
times you may miss out on your entries.
It's normal, but at the end of the day,
what we are looking at is what the win
rate and how you are making money while
protecting your capital. So that is it.
[Music]